Vera Wadsworth Beggs Papers, 1932-1969
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Vera Wadsworth Beggs papers
1932-1969
Beggs, Vera W. (Vera Wadsworth), d. 1968.
MS 15
2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Pacifist; Suffragist; Civic leader; International relations specialist. This small collection of Vera Beggs' papers includes extensive correspondence to and from Carrie Chapman Catt describing women's rights and peace activism and organizations.
Biographical Note
Pacifist, suffragist, civic leader, and international relations specialist, Vera Beggs worked closely with Carrie Chapman Catt from 1933 to 1938 as chairman of the Marathon Round Tables, a study and discussion project concerned with U. S. foreign policy carried on through the National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War (NCCCW). Beggs chaired the NCCCW in the early 1940s and continued to be involved with its successor, the Women's Action Committee for Lasting Peace. She served as chairman of the Department of International Relations for the General Federation of Women's Clubs and in this capacity organized and conducted a Good Neighbor Tour of South America in 1940. Vera Wadsworth Beggs' date of birth is unknown; she died in 1968.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Vera Wadsworth Beggs Papers consist of correspondence, clippings, and organization files. The collection contains extensive correspondence of Carrie Chapman Catt describing women's rights work and activities for peace. The papers also contain materials relating to the General Federation of Women's Clubs, the International Alliance of Women for Suffrage and Equal Citizenship, the National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War, the Foreign Policy Association, the New York Herald Tribune's Inter-American Conferences, and the Woman's Action Committee for Lasting Peace.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Search Terms
International relations specialists--United States--Biography--Sources; Women and peace--History--20th century--Sources; Women--Suffrage--United States-History--Sources; Women's rights--International cooperation--History--20th century--Sources; Beggs, Vera W. (Vera Wadsworth), d. 1968.; Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947; General Federation of Women's Clubs; International Alliance of Women for Suffrage and Equal Citizenship; National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War (U.S.)--History; Peace movements--History--20th century--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
Additional materials relating to Vera Wadsworth Beggs are housed at the Rutgers University Archives.
- Contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Carrie Chapman Catt: correspondence and printed material, 1933-54 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and clippings, 1935-68 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 1)
  - Script of pageant, "The Nations Speak," by the International Relations Department of the New Jersey State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1950-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Articles, notes, and printed material, 1940-65 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alaska Daily Press, Juneau Woman's Club Edition, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- International Alliance of Women for Suffrage and Equal Citizenship: papers from congress in Istanbul, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War (Box 1)
  - Proceedings for annual fall meeting, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Administrative Committee, 1941-43 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marathon Round Table Discussion Program: printed material, 1937-39 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conference materials and other papers, 1934-42 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous printed material, 1934-50 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Foreign Policy Association: Headline books, 1936-39 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- New York Herald Tribune, Inter-American Conferences: agendas, speeches, and miscellaneous papers, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Woman's Action Committee for Lasting Peace: mailings, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)